Guide to the Dorothy Porter Wesley Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Series III. Research Files, 1847-2004
  - African American Literature and Culture, 1797-2011
    - General Research Files
      - Black Studies Programs
        - Publications, 1969-1970 (Box 194, Folder 1731)
        - University of Iowa, 1969-1970 (Box 195, Folder 1732-1733)
        - University of Maryland, 1969- (Box 195, Folder 1734)
        - University of Utah (oversize), 1970- (Box 275 (Oversize), Folder 2541)
        - Yale University, 1972-1973 (Box 195, Folder 1735)
        - Clippings, Circa 1948-1994 (Box 195, Folder 1735a)
        - Clippings, 1966-1994 (Box 275 (Oversize), Folder 2542)
      - Charles C. Cook, 1923- (Box 195, Folder 1736)
      - Charles H. Garvin, Undated (Box 195, Folder 1737)
      - Charlotte Forten, 1980-1988 (Box 195, Folder 1738-1739)
      - Charlotte Forten, 1980- (Box 275 (Oversize), Folder 2543)
      - "The Colored Aristocracy of St. Louis" by Cyprian Clamorgan, 1858, 1970-1971 (Box 195, Folder 1740)
      - The Complete Fortune Teller and Dream Book By Chloe Russel, 1989- (Box 195, Folder 1741)
      - The Crisis (Front page), 1922- (Box 195, Folder 1742)
      - David Ruggles
        - Dorothy Porter Wesley Writings on David Ruggles
          - "David Ruggles, An Apostle of Human Rights", 1943- (Box 196, Folder 1743)
          - "Dr.' David Ruggles Hydropathic Practitioner", Undated (Box 196, Folder 1744)
          - "Northampton Won Widespread Fame Through Water Cure Establishments; Taught Many Value of Diet, Fresh Air, Rest, 1954- (Box 196, Folder 1745)
          - Untitled Writings, Undated (Box 196, Folder 1746)
        - American Antiquarian Society, 1975- (Box 197, Folder 1747)
        - Correspondence concerning David Ruggles research, 1942-1956 (Box 197, Folder 1748)
        - David Ruggles Papers 1834-1850, Circa 1942-1975 (Box 197, Folder 1749-1750)
        - David Ruggles Papers 1834-1850, Circa 1942-1975 (Box 197, Folder 1751)
        - Discrimination against transports, Circa 1949 (Box 197, Folder 1752)
        - Genealogy, Circa 1949 (Box 197, Folder 1753)
        - Letters to and from David Ruggles, 1836-1846 (copies), Undated (Box 197, Folder 1754)
        - Libel, Circa 1949 (Box 197, Folder 1755)
        - Watercure, 1949- (Box 197, Folder 1756-1757)
        - Notes, Circa 1942-1975 (Box 197, Folder 1758-1759)
        - Notes, Circa 1942-1975 (Box 198, Folder 1760-1763)
      - Frances Grant, 1973- (Box 198, Folder 1764)
      - Francis L. Cardoza, 1869- (Box 198, Folder 1765)
      - Handy Brothers Music Company (oversize), 1936- (Box 275 (Oversize), Folder 2544)
      - Illustrations, 1988- (Box 198, Folder 1766)
      - Ira Aldridge, 1991- (Box 198, Folder 1767)
      - Isaiah Isaacs Wears (copies), 1894- (Box 198, Folder 1768)
      - Isaiah Isaacs Wears (copies), 1859-1869 (Box 275 (Oversize), Folder 2545)
      - James Weldon Johnson (oversize), 1934- (Box 275 (Oversize), Folder 2546)
      - Jaun Latino, Undated (Box 198, Folder 1769)
      - John Clarkson, Undated (Box 198, Folder 1770)
      - Johnson C. Smith University, 1943- (Box 198, Folder 1771)
      - Joshua H. Jones, 1913-1989 (Box 198, Folder 1772)
      - Julia Hamilton Smith, 1961-1967 (Box 198, Folder 1773)
      - Julia Hamilton Smith, 1961-1967 (Box 199, Folder 1774)
      - Katharine Cornell, 1926-2009 (Box 199, Folder 1775)
      - Liberation Journal, 1967- (Box 199, Folder 1776)
      - Libraries: Detroit, 1927- (Box 199, Folder 1777)
      - Libraries: Schomburg, 1955-1985 (Box 199, Folder 1778)
        - Oversize, 1955- (Box 275 (Oversize), Folder 2547)
      - Empty, Undated (Box 199, Folder 1779)
      - Lorenzo Greene, Undated (Box 199, Folder 1780)
      - Louisville Colored High School: Commencement, 1896- (Box 199, Folder 1781)
      - Mae Miller (oversize), 1982- (Box 275 (Oversize), Folder 2548)
      - Margaret Allison Bonds, 1934- (Box 199, Folder 1782)
      - Maria Stewart, Undated (Box 199, Folder 1783)
      - Maria Louisa Baldwin, 1922-1949 (Box 199, Folder 1784)
      - May Miller Sullivan, Undated (Box 199, Folder 1785)
      - McGirt's Magazine, 1971- (Box 199, Folder 1786)
      - "Memoirs of the Life, Religious Experience, Ministerial, Travels and Labours of Mrs. Zilpha Elaw, An American Female of Colour; Together With Some Account of the Great Religious Revivals in America", 1846, Undated (Box 199, Folder 1787)
      - Miriam Matthews, Undated (Box 199, Folder 1788)
      - Mwalimu Chorus, 1939-1973 (Box 199, Folder 1789)
      - National Afro-American Museum, Wilberforce, 1982- (Box 199, Folder 1790)
        - Oversize, 1982- (Box 275 (Oversize), Folder 2549)
      - National Council of Negro Women Project, Bibliography 19th Century Newspaper and Periodical Souces of Black Women's History, 1978- (Box 199, Folder 1791)
      - Negro Society for Historical Research, Undated (Box 199, Folder 1792)
      - Negro History Bulletin, 1937-2002 (Box 199, Folder 1793)
      - Negro Union, Baltimore, 1907- (Box 200, Folder 1794)
      - Notable Negros, Circa 1940 (Box 200, Folder 1795)
      - Odd Fellows Journal, fraternities (oversize), 1914- (Box 275 (Oversize), Folder 2550)
      - "One Hundred Distinguished Leaders" by Charles Alexander, 1899- (Box 200, Folder 1796)
      - "Panorama of Negro History from 1492 to Today", Excerpts from the Folkways/Scholastic Record Library, 33 1/3 RPM, 1968- (Box 200, Folder 1797)
      - Patrick Henry Reason, 1975-1988 (Box 200, Folder 1798-1801)
      - Pearlie's Prattle by Pearlie Cox (copy), Circa 1950 (Box 200, Folder 1802)
      - Philadelphia Library Company, 1967- (Box 200, Folder 1803)
      - Phillis Wheatley Collection, 1947- (Box 200, Folder 1804)
      - Program Corporation of America, Undated (Box 200, Folder 1805)
      - Publications, 1925-1994 (Box 200, Folder 1806-1807)
      - Reprints, photostat copies of early letters (1861-1903), Undated (Box 201, Folder 1808-1812)
        - Oversize, 1873-1874 (Box 275 (Oversize), Folder 2551)
      - Richard T. Greener, 2001- (Box 201, Folder 1813)
      - Robert Hayden, 1975-1976 (Box 201, Folder 1814)
      - St. Paul's School, 1922- (Box 201, Folder 1815)
      - Separate and Unequal essays, Undated (Box 201, Folder 1816)
      - "The Sexual Mountain and Black Women Writers" by Calvin C. Hernton, 1987- (Box 201, Folder 1817)
      - Sidney Bechet, Undated (Box 201, Folder 1818)
      - "Starvation of Young Black Minds: The Effect of Book Boycotts in South Africa", Sponsored by the Association of American Publishers and the Fund for Free Expression, 1989- (Box 202, Folder 1819)
      - Tuskegee Institute (blank postcards), Undated (Box 202, Folder 1820)
      - William A. Joiner (postcards), 1907-1914 (Box 202, Folder 1821)
      - William Carol Bolivar, 1907-1912 (Box 202, Folder 1822)
      - William H. H. Hart, Undated (Box 202, Folder 1823)
      - William H. Sheppard, 1958-2011 (Box 202, Folder 1824)
      - William Montague Cobb, 1973-2002 (Box 202, Folder 1825-1826)
      - Women, 1992- (Box 202, Folder 1827-1828)
      - Notes, Circa 1928-2002 (Box 203, Folder 1829-1835)
      - Notes, Circa 1928-2002 (Box 204, Folder 1836-1841)
      - Notes, 1928-1941 (Box 275 (Oversize), Folder 2552)
    - Early Negro Writings
      - Drafts, Circa 1963-1972 (Box 205, Folder 1842-1847)
      - General Research
        - "Constitution of the African Marine Fund, for the Relief of the Distressed Orphans, and Poor Members, of This Fund" Printed by John C. Totten (copy), 1810- (Box 205, Folder 1848)
        - "Constitution and By-Laws of the Phoenix Society of the City of New York" (copy), 1835- (Box 205, Folder 1849)
        - "Constitution and Rules to be Observed and Kept by the Friendly Society of St. Thomas's African Church, of Philadelphia" printed by W.W. Woodward (copy), 1797- (Box 205, Folder 1850)
        - "Conventional address" by Abraham D. Shadd (copy), 1833- (Box 205, Folder 1851)
        - Early Negro Writings Reviews, 1971-1977 (Box 205, Folder 1852)
        - Early Negro Writings Reviews, 1971-1977 (Box 206, Folder 1853)
        - Illustations for Book, Undated (Box 206, Folder 1854-1861)
        - "Memorial of the Free People of Colour" (Copy), 1826- (Box 207, Folder 1862)
        - "Missonary Pioneer" (copy), 1827- (Box 207, Folder 1863)
        - Negatives, Undated (Box 207, Folder 1864-1865)
        - Orders, 1963-1964 (Box 207, Folder 1866)
        - "Proceedings of a Convention of Delegates", Undated (Box 207, Folder 1867)
        - The Senate and House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, Undated (Box 207, Folder 1868)
        - Sources, Circa 1968-1972 (Box 207, Folder 1869)
        - Titles not to be used or Duplicates, Circa 1968-1972 (Box 207, Folder 1870)
        - Notes, Circa 1963-1972 (Box 207, Folder 1871-1873)
  - Afro-Braziliana research
    The Afro-Braziliana research subseries contains materials documenting Dorothy Porter Wesley's travels to Brazil collecting information and items for the Moorland Spingarn Research Center and for her bibliography Afro-Braziliana: A Working Bibliography (1978).
    - General research
      - Abolition, 1953- (Box 208, Folder 1874)
      - "African Culture in Brazil" by Milton Hare, Circa 1966 (Box 208, Folder 1875)
      - Empty, Undated (Box 208, Folder 1876)
      - Alzofon Books, 1974- (Box 208, Folder 1877)
      - Alzofon Books, 1951- (Box 276 (Oversize), Folder 2553)
      - Authors, 1943-1954 (Box 208, Folder 1878)
      - Authors, 1952-1953 (Box 276 (Oversize), Folder 2554)
      - Azucena by Jose Cid Perez, 1943- (Box 208, Folder 1879)
      - "Book Report on the Rebellion in Backlands" by Dorothy Porter Wesley, 1944- (Box 208, Folder 1880)
      - Brazillian American Cultural Institute, 1965- (Box 208, Folder 1881)
      - Brazillian Authors of Negro Ancestry, 1943- (Box 208, Folder 1882-1883)
      - Brazillian Books and Booksellers, 1973- (Box 208, Folder 1884)
      - Brazilians in Lagos, 1963- (Box 208, Folder 1885)
      - "The Brazillian Racial Situation" by Donald Pierson, 1944- (Box 208, Folder 1886)
      - Carnaval, 1947-1953 (Box 208, Folder 1887)
      - Catalogs, Circa 1951-1954 (Box 209, Folder 1888)
      - Colonial Period, 1974- (Box 209, Folder 1889)
      - Congresso do Negro Brasileiro, 1937-1950 (Box 209, Folder 1890)
      - Entertainers, 1952-1953 (Box 209, Folder 1891)
      - Entertainers, 1944- (Box 276 (Oversize), Folder 2555)
      - Individuals, 1952- (Box 209, Folder 1892)
      - Latin American Literature, Rosenwald Project, Undated (Box 209, Folder 1893)
      - Latin American Materials on the Negro, Undated (Box 209, Folder 1894)
      - Luso-Brazilian Studies, 1950- (Box 209, Folder 1895)
      - Maps, Undated (Box 276 (Oversize), Folder 2556)
      - The Negro in the Brazilian Abolition Movement by Dorothy Porter Wesley, Undated (Box 209, Folder 1896)
      - Poetry, Circa 1953 (Box 209, Folder 1897)
      - Poetry, 1953- (Box 276 (Oversize), Folder 2557)
      - Postcards and photographs, 1951- (Box 209, Folder 1898)
      - Publications, 1923-1977 (Box 209, Folder 1899-1900)
      - Publications, 1923-1977 (Box 210, Folder 1901-1902)
      - Race Question, 1952- (Box 210, Folder 1903)
      - Race Question, 1949-1951 (Box 276 (Oversize), Folder 2558)
      - Race Relations, Circa 1944-1993 (Box 210, Folder 1904)
      - "Reflections of an Afro-Braziliano" by Abdias do Nascimento, 1978-1979 (Box 210, Folder 1905)
      - Religious Cults, 1952- (Box 210, Folder 1906)
      - Religious Cults, 1952-1953 (Box 276 (Oversize), Folder 2559)
      - Sample lists outlines, Undated (Box 210, Folder 1907)
      - Sao Paulo, 1952- (Box 210, Folder 1908)
      - Sao Paolo, 1951- (Box 276 (Oversize), Folder 2560)
      - Silva Alvarenga, Undated (Box 210, Folder 1909)
      - Society and Culture, Undated (Box 210, Folder 1910)
      - South America trip, bills, tickets and booklists, 1959- (Box 211, Folder 1911)
      - Subjects, names and notes, Circa 1952 (Box 211, Folder 1912)
      - Teatro do Negro and Abdias Nascimento, 1951-1953 (Box 211, Folder 1913)
      - Travel expenses for 4th International Colloquium on Luso Brazilian Studies in Salvador, 1959-1960 (Box 211, Folder 1914)
      - Untitled author lists, 1958-1959 (Box 211, Folder 1915)
      - Untitled author lists, 1944- (Box 276 (Oversize), Folder 2561)
      - Notes, Circa 1950-1978 (Box 211, Folder 1916-1918)
      - Notes, Circa 1950-1978 (Box 212, Folder 1919-1925)
      - Notes, Circa 1950-1978 (Box 213, Folder 1926-1928)
      - Clippings, 1944-1974 (Box 213, Folder 1929-1930)
      - Clippings, 1944-1954 (Box 276a (Oversize), Folder 2562-2562c)
    - Afro-Braziliana: A Working Bibliography (1978), (research and drafts), Circa 1978
      Contains files related to authors used in Afro-Braziliana: A Working Bibliography (1978)
      - Author Files
        - Alameida Rosa, Francisco Octaviano, 1825-1889 (Box 213, Folder 1931)
        - Amado, Jorge, 1912 (Box 213, Folder 1932)
        - Andrade, Mario de, 1893-1945 (Box 213, Folder 1933)
        - Anjos, Augusto de Carvalho Rodrigues Dos, 1884-1913 (Box 214, Folder 1934)
        - Austregesilo Rodrigues Lima, Antonio 1876 (Box 214, Folder 1935)
        - Barreto, Joao Paulo Alberto Coelho, 1881-1921 (Box 214, Folder 1936)
        - Barreto de Mendezes, Tobias, 1839-1889 (Box 214, Folder 1937)
        - Bilac, Olavo dos Guimares, 1865-1918 (Box 214, Folder 1938)
        - Brito, Francisco de Paula, 1809-1861 (Box 214, Folder 1939)
        - Brito, Raimundo de Farias, 1862-1917 (Box 214, Folder 1940)
        - Caldas Brabosa, Domingos, 1740-1800 (Box 214, Folder 1941)
        - Campos, Humberto de, 1886-1934 (Box 214, Folder 1942)
        - Carneiro, Edison de Souza, 1912-1972 (Box 214, Folder 1943)
        - Castriciano de Souza, Henrique, 1874-1947 (Box 214, Folder 1944)
        - Castro Alves, Antonio de, 1847-1871 (Box 214, Folder 1945)
        - Correa, Viriato 1883- (Box 214, Folder 1946)
        - Cruz e Souza, Joao da, 1862-1898 (Box 214, Folder 1947)
        - Dantas, Raymundo Souza, 1923 (Box 214, Folder 1948)
        - Delfino dos Santos, Juiz, 1834-1910 (Box 214, Folder 1949)
        - Dias de Mesquito, Teofilo Oderico, 1854-1889 (Box 214, Folder 1950)
        - Ferreira da Veiga, Evaristo, 1799-1837 (Box 214, Folder 1951)
        - Fontes, Hermes, 1888-1930 (Box 214, Folder 1952)
        - Gama, Domincio da, 1862-1925 (Box 214, Folder 1953)
        - Gama, Jose Basilio da, 1740-1795 (Box 214, Folder 1954)
        - Gama, Luiz Gonzaga Pinto da, 1830-1882 (Box 214, Folder 1955)
        - Goes, Fernando (Box 214, Folder 1956)
        - Gomes Pimenta, Silverio, 1840-1922 (Box 214, Folder 1957)
        - Goncalves Crespo, Candido Antonia, 1846-1883 (Box 214, Folder 1958)
        - Goncalves Dias, Antonio, 1823-1864 (Box 214, Folder 1959)
        - Goncalves, Francisco de Paula, 1899-1927 (Box 214, Folder 1960)
        - Guerra, Gregorio de Matos, 1623-1696 (Box 215, Folder 1961)
        - Jurandir, Dalcidio (Box 215, Folder 1962)
        - Lima Barreto, Afonso Henrique de, 1881-1992 (Box 215, Folder 1963)
        - Lima, Jorge de, 1893-1953 (Box 215, Folder 1964)
        - Lopes, Bernardino da Costa, 1859-1916 (Box 215, Folder 1965)
        - Lopes de Moura, Caetano, 1780-1960 (Box 215, Folder 1966)
        - Machado de Assis, Joaquim Maria, 1839-1908 (Box 215, Folder 1967)
        - Martens Junior, Jose Isidoro, 1860-1904 (Box 215, Folder 1968)
        - Melo, Agnelo Rodrigues de (Box 215, Folder 1969)
        - Moraes, Antonio Evaristo de, 1871-1939 (Box 215, Folder 1970)
        - Nascentes, Antenor, 1886-1972 (Box 215, Folder 1971)
        - Nina Rodriques, Raymundo, 1862-1906 (Box 215, Folder 1972)
        - Palhares, Victoriano Jose Marinho, 1840-1890 (Box 215, Folder 1973)
        - Paltrocinio, Jose do Carlos, 1853-1905 (Box 215, Folder 1974)
        - Patrocinio Filho, Jose do, 1885-1929 (Box 215, Folder 1975)
        - Pereira Reboucas, Antonio, 1798-1880 (Box 215, Folder 1976)
        - Pereira, Reboucas, Filho Antonio, 1839-1874 (Box 215, Folder 1977)
        - Querino, Manuel Raimundo, 1851-1923 (Box 215, Folder 1978)
        - Raimundo, Jacques (Box 215, Folder 1979)
        - Ramos, Alberto Guerreiro (Box 215, Folder 1980)
        - Reboucas, Andre Pinto, 1838-1898 (Box 215, Folder 1981)
        - Rego, Joao de Deus do, 1867-1902 (Box 215, Folder 1982)
        - Rego, Jose Lins do, 1910-1957 (Box 215, Folder 1983)
        - Rocha, Justiniano Jose da, 1812-1862 (Box 215, Folder 1984)
        - Rodrigues, Ironides (Box 215, Folder 1985)
        - Saldanha, Jose da Natividade, 1796-1830 (Box 215, Folder 1986)
        - Sampaio, Theodoro Fernandes, 1855-1937 (Box 215, Folder 1987)
        - Santos, Hermeterio Jose dos, 1858 (Box 215, Folder 1988)
        - Santos, Jose Maria dos, 1877-1954 (Box 215, Folder 1989)
        - Silva, J. Romao da (Box 215, Folder 1990)
        - Silva Rabello, Laurindo Jose da, 1826-1864 (Box 215, Folder 1991)
        - Silva Alvarenga, Manoel Ignacio da, 1749-1814 (Box 216, Folder 1992)
        - Teixeira E. Souza, Antonio Goncalves, 1812-1861 (Box 216, Folder 1993)
        - Titara, Ladislau dos Santos, 1801-1861 (Box 216, Folder 1994)
        - Trinidade, Solano (Box 216, Folder 1995)
        - Vianna, Francisco Jose de Oliveira, 1885-1951 (Box 216, Folder 1996)
        - Viera, Antonio, 1608-1697 (Box 216, Folder 1997)
        - Wanderly, Joao Barao de Cotegipe, 1815-1889 (Box 216, Folder 1998)
      - Corrections, 1978- (Box 216, Folder 1999)
      - Dedications, Circa 1978 (Box 216, Folder 2000)
      - Outline, Circa 1978 (Box 216, Folder 2001)
      - Preface, Circa 1978 (Box 216, Folder 2002)
      - Poetry, Circa 1978 (Box 216, Folder 2003)
      - Revisions, Circa 1978 (Box 216, Folder 2004)
      - Reviews, 1978-1979 (Box 216, Folder 2005)
      - Royalties, 1984-1992 (Box 216, Folder 2006)
      - Subjects, Circa 1978
        - Bibliographies (Box 216, Folder 2007)
        - General Works (Box 216, Folder 2008)
        - Travel (Box 216, Folder 2009)
        - Traveller's Accounts of Brazil (Box 217, Folder 2010)
        - African Slave Trade, Slavery, and Abolition (Box 217, Folder 2011-2013)
        - Slave Insurrections and the Quilombo of Palmares (Box 217, Folder 2014)
        - Bandeirante Movement (Box 217, Folder 2015)
        - Additional Aspects of Afro-Brazilian History (Box 217, Folder 2016)
        - History (Box 217, Folder 2017)
        - Social conditions and race relations (Box 217, Folder 2018)
        - Sociology (Box 217, Folder 2019)
        - Sociology and Anthropology (Box 217, Folder 2020)
        - Medicine and Health (Box 218, Folder 2021)
        - Africanisms in the Brazilian Portuguese Language (Box 218, Folder 2022)
        - African Influence on Brazilian Cookery (Box 218, Folder 2023)
        - Art (Box 218, Folder 2024)
        - Art and Artists (Box 218, Folder 2025)
        - Music, Dance and Carnival (Box 218, Folder 2026-2027)
        - Folklore (Box 218, Folder 2028-2029)
        - Religion (Box 218, Folder 2030-2031)
        - Football-Soccer (Box 218, Folder 2032)
        - Literature (Box 219, Folder 2033)
        - Anthologies (Box 219, Folder 2034)
        - History and Criticisim (Box 219, Folder 2035)
        - Poetry with and Afro-Brazilian theme (Box 219, Folder 2036)
        - Prose with Afro-Brazilian theme (Box 219, Folder 2037)
        - Prose Fiction (Box 219, Folder 2038)
        - Drama (Box 219, Folder 2039)
        - Individual and Collective Biography (Box 219, Folder 2040)
  - Caribbean and South American Research
    Contains clippings and notes documenting the research conducted by Dorothy Porter Wesley during her travels to the Caribbean and South America.
    - Bibliographies, Circa 1961 (Box 220, Folder 2041)
    - La Biblioteca Colombia, Undated (Box 220, Folder 2042)
    - La Biblioteca Colombia, 1982-1992 (Box 276a (Oversize), Folder 2563)
    - Books, 1944- (Box 220, Folder 2043)
    - Caribbean literature, 1932-1961 (Box 220, Folder 2044)
    - Caribbean literature, 1961- (Box 276a (Oversize), Folder 2564)
    - Cuban booklists and notes, Undated (Box 220, Folder 2045)
    - Haiti, 1966- (Box 220, Folder 2046)
    - Mexico, 1944- (Box 220, Folder 2047)
    - Rachel Pringle, Undated (Box 220, Folder 2048)
    - San Martin De Porres, Circa 1971 (Box 220, Folder 2049)
    - Notes, Undated (Box 220, Folder 2050)
    - South America clippings, 1960-1974 (Box 220, Folder 2051)
    - South America clippings, 1960- (Box 276a (Oversize), Folder 2565)
  - Remond Family Research Papers
    The Remond Family Papers consists of the research conducted by Dorothy Porter Wesley on the abolitionist Remond family of Salem, Massachusetts, specifically Sarah Parker Remond and Charles Lenox Remond. A majority of the subseries consist of articles, clippings and notes documenting the Remond family.
    - Dorothy Porter Wesley Research on the Remond Family
      - Correspondence related to Remond Family Research, 1945-1995 (Box 221, Folder 2052-2054)
      - Bibliographical notes, Circa 1976-1981 (Box 221, Folder 2055)
      - A Biography of Sarah Parker Remond, project notes, 1972-1985 (Box 221, Folder 2056)
      - A Biography of Sarah Parker Remond, project notes, 1985- (Box 277 (Oversize), Folder 2566)
      - Charles Lenox Remond, 1810-1873, By Dorothy Porter Wesley essay and notes, Circa 1974 (Box 221, Folder 2057)
      - Ford Foundation Report: Remond-Grant, 1972-1978 (Box 221, Folder 2058-2059)
      - Ford Foundation Report: Remond-Grant, 1972-1978 (Box 221, Folder 2060)
      - Remonds in 19th Century Europe, 1989- (Box 222, Folder 2061)
      - The Remonds of Salem: A Forgotten Nineteenth Century Family, Circa 1972-1973 (Box 222, Folder 2062-2063)
      - "The Remonds of Salem, Massachusettes: A Nineteenth-Century Family Revisited", 1985-1986 (Box 222, Folder 2064-2067)
      - Remond Research Fund, 1977-1978 (Box 223, Folder 2068)
      - Remond, Sarah Parker, Undated (Box 223, Folder 2069)
      - "Sarah Parker Remond Abolitionist and Physician", 1935- (Box 223, Folder 2070-2071)
      - Sarah Pintor, Probate Court, Undated (Box 223, Folder 2072)
      - Sources to be checked, 1971- (Box 223, Folder 2073)
      - Travel expenses, 1972-1973 (Box 223, Folder 2074-2075)
      - Untitled Writings, Circa 1971-1978 (Box 223, Folder 2076)
    - Remond Family Papers
      - Empty, Undated (Box 223a, Folder 2077)
      - Census Records 1755-1870 (copies), Circa 1973 (Box 223a, Folder 2078-2081)
      - Chronology of Remond family, Undated (Box 223a, Folder 2082-2084)
      - Directories of Salem notes, Undated (Box 223a, Folder 2085)
      - Genealogy, deaths, wills and obituaries, Undated (Box 224, Folder 2086-2091)
      - Agnes Ellen Babcock, Undated (Box 224, Folder 2092)
      - Cecelia Babcock, marriage certificates, leases, correspondence and notes, Circa 1891-1916 (Box 224, Folder 2093)
      - Cecelia Babcock, marriage certificates, leases, correspondence and notes, Circa 1891-1916 (Box 225, Folder 2094)
      - Charles Babcock, Undated (Box 225, Folder 2095)
      - Edward P. Cassell, Undated (Box 225, Folder 2096)
      - John M. Cassell, Undated (Box 225, Folder 2097)
      - Maritchie Cassell, 1978- (Box 225, Folder 2098)
      - Cornelius Lenox, Undated (Box 225, Folder 2099)
      - John Lenox, Undated (Box 225, Folder 2100)
      - Louisa Lenox, Undated (Box 225, Folder 2101)
      - Perry Lenox, 1975- (Box 225, Folder 2102)
      - Caroline E. Putnam, Undated (Box 225, Folder 2103-2104)
      - Edmund Quincy Putnam, 1972-1975 (Box 225, Folder 2105)
      - Edmund Quincy Putnam, 1972-1975 (Box 226, Folder 2106-2111)
      - Edmund Quincy Putnam, 1986-1990 (Box 277 (Oversize), Folder 2567-2568)
      - George Putnam, Undated (Box 226, Folder 2112)
      - Joseph Putnam, Undated (Box 226, Folder 2113)
      - Quincy Putnam, Undated (Box 226, Folder 2114)